<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Quickstart on Command Launcher</title><link>https://criteo.github.io/command-launcher/docs/quickstart/</link><description>Recent content in Quickstart on Command Launcher</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2022 17:21:45 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://criteo.github.io/command-launcher/docs/quickstart/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Binary install</title><link>https://criteo.github.io/command-launcher/docs/quickstart/binary-install/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2022 17:25:20 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://criteo.github.io/command-launcher/docs/quickstart/binary-install/</guid><description>Download pre-built binaries #
Pre-built binaries can be downloaded from the Github release page. Copy the binary into your PATH.
The default pre-built binary is named cola (Command Launcher), if you want to use a different name, you can build your own binaries from source. See build from source.
For example, in each release, we also build a binary named cdt (Criteo Dev Toolkit). If you prefer to download cdt, please replace cola to cdt in the examples from the documents.</description></item><item><title>Build from source</title><link>https://criteo.github.io/command-launcher/docs/quickstart/build-from-source/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2022 17:34:04 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://criteo.github.io/command-launcher/docs/quickstart/build-from-source/</guid><description>Why does the binary name matter? #
Command launcher is designed for both enterprise and individual usage. According to your context, you might want to call it differently. For example, at Criteo, we call it &amp;ldquo;Criteo Dev Toolkit&amp;rdquo;. The binary name is used for several default configurations, for example, command launcher home $HOME/.[APP_NAME], additional resources environment prefix [APP_NAME]_, etc.
The default pre-built binary is call cola (Command Launcher), which means that the default home folder is $HOME/.</description></item><item><title>Quick Start</title><link>https://criteo.github.io/command-launcher/docs/quickstart/first-command/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2022 17:01:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://criteo.github.io/command-launcher/docs/quickstart/first-command/</guid><description>Preparation #
If you want to use the default command launcher binary name (cola): install command launcher following the guide Binary install. Or if you prefer a different binary name, build command launcher from source: Build from source
In Criteo, we call it cdt, (Criteo Dev Toolkit)
In this tutorial, we will use the binary name cola.
To check your command launcher installation, run following command:
cola config It should list all your configurations.</description></item></channel></rss>