<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>News on Command Launcher</title><link>https://criteo.github.io/command-launcher/categories/news/</link><description>Recent content in News on Command Launcher</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2023 09:19:42 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://criteo.github.io/command-launcher/categories/news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>✨ 1.8.0 Release</title><link>https://criteo.github.io/command-launcher/blog/1.8.0-release/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2023 09:19:42 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://criteo.github.io/command-launcher/blog/1.8.0-release/</guid><description>Release notes #
✨Support multiple remote registry. From version 1.8.0, you are able to define multiple remote registries. Command launcher synchronizes the commands with all these remote registries at the end of each command execution. This is useful for several scenarios: for example, supporting internal or experimental commands, different teams target their commands to different group of audience.
✨Built-in command remote command to mange multiple remote registries.
remote list: list all remote registries remote delete: delete specific remote registry remote add: add a new remote registry ✨Built-in package management related commands are regrouped into package command:</description></item><item><title>✨ 1.7.0 Release Note</title><link>https://criteo.github.io/command-launcher/blog/1.7.0-release-note/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2022 09:19:42 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://criteo.github.io/command-launcher/blog/1.7.0-release-note/</guid><description>Release notes #
✨New mechanism to access resources with user consent, resources required user consent: username password auth_token log_level ✨New system package with system command. Now supports two types of system command: login: extends the built-in login command metrics: extends the built-in metrics ✨New package management with new built-in commands: list: list installed local and dropin packages and remote packages. It also provides the possibility to show the installed commands install: install dropin packages from git repository or remote/local zip file delete: delete installed dropin packages ✨New URL convention for command launcher self update.</description></item><item><title>✨ 1.6.0 Release</title><link>https://criteo.github.io/command-launcher/blog/1.6.0-release/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2022 09:19:42 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://criteo.github.io/command-launcher/blog/1.6.0-release/</guid><description>Release notes #
Add the PackageDir context variable to reference the package&amp;rsquo;s directory, same as the Cache and Root context variables. Cache and Root variables are deprecated. Extend the format of the flag definition. Now it is possible to add bool type flags: [name] \t [shorthand] \t [description] \t [type] \t [default]. Currently, two types are supported: string and bool. both type and default value are optional, by default, the type is &amp;ldquo;string&amp;rdquo;, and the default value is the empty string.</description></item></channel></rss>